http://www.pasadena.edu/privacy.php

Campus Access Restrictions PCC is closed to student and public access. Coming to campus? Take our health survey. For resources and tools we’re using during this time visit Remote Campus Information & Updates.
Close menu button
Apply Now
Quicklinks
Schedule of Classes
Maps
Canvas
Directory
Library
What are you looking for?
Enter your search query here then either click the "Search Site" or the "Search People" button.
Enter your search query here then either click "Search Site" or "Search People."
At Pasadena City College (PCC), we are committed to protecting your privacy and making
it more efficient to interact with our Web site. We recognize your right to know what
information is being collected about you and how that information will be used, as
well as our legal obligations to limit collection and protect what we do collect.
You do not have to give us personal information to visit our site. Sometimes we do
need information to provide services that you request, and this commitment of privacy
explains our online information practices.
This policy is consistent with the provisions of the Internet Security and Privacy
Act, the Freedom of Information Law, and the Personal Privacy Protection Law. Pasadena
City College further complies with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA)
as it pertains to student records updated online.
This Statement of Internet Privacy applies to the pasadena.edu Web site and governs
data collection and usage. By using the pasadena.edu website, you consent to the data
practices described in this statement.
PCC does not collect any personal information about you unless you provide that information
voluntarily by sending e-mail, completing an online request, registration or an application
form.
Information Collected
The pasadena.edu Web site collects personal information (first and last name, home
or other physical address, email address, telephone number, or other identifiers that
permit the physical or online contacting of an individual) only if specifically and
knowingly provided by you. For purposes of this policy, "personal information" means
any information concerning a natural person which, because of name, number, symbol,
mark, or other identifier, can be used to identify that natural person.
The pasadena.edu Web site also collects anonymous demographic information for statistical
purposes and the analyses of user behavior in order to measure interest in the various
areas of our site. We will disclose this information to third parties only in aggregate
form.
Information Collected Automatically When You Visit pasadena.edu
When visiting pasadena.edu, PCC automatically collects and stores the following information
about your visit:
The Internet domain (for example, "xcompany.com" if you use a private Internet access
account) and IP address (an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned
to your computer on the Internet.
The type of browser used, its version and the operating system on which that browser
is running
The Web page from which you hyperlinked to the current Web page
The date and time of the visit
The pages that were visited and the amount of time spent at each page
None of the automatically collected information constitutes personal information by
the Internet Privacy and Security Act. This automatically collected information is
is collected for statistical analysis and is used to learn how users are interacting
with our Web site and to maintain or improve the quality of the Web site.
The automatically collected information is not collected for commercial marketing
purposes and PCC is not authorized to sell or otherwise disclose the information collected
from pasadena.edu for commercial marketing purposes.
Information You Send Via Email
During your visit to pasadena.edu you may send an email to PCC. Your e-mail address
and the contents of your message will be collected. The information collected is not
limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and graphic information formats
included in the message. Your email address and the information included in your message
will be used to respond to you, to address issues you identify, to improve this Web
site, or to forward your message to another PCC department for appropriate action.
Your e-mail address is not collected for commercial purposes and PCC is not authorized
to sell or otherwise disclose your e-mail address for commercial purposes. Except
for authorized law enforcement investigations or, as required by law, we do not share
our email with any other organizations.
Remember that e-mail is not necessarily secure against interception. If your communication
is very sensitive, or includes information such as your bank account, charge card,
or social security number, you should send it by mail.
Information You Submit to Us Via an Online Request, Application or Registration Form
During your visit to pasadena.edu you may complete a transaction such as an online
application or an online information request form. The information collected by PCC,
including personal information volunteered by you in completing the form, application
or transaction, is used by PCC only for the purposes for which it was provided and
will not be shared with another entity except as prescribed by law. Pasadena City
College may provide or distribute certain lists and statistical reports of regulatory
information as provided by law, but no personal information is sold or distributed
for commercial purposes.
PCC does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of
13 or create profiles of children under the age of 13. Users are cautioned, however,
that the collection of personal information submitted in an email will be treated
as though it was submitted by an adult, and may, unless exempted from access by federal
or state law, be subject to public access.
Electronic Commerce Precautions
Some of our Web pages allow you to make donations, register and pay for classes, etc.
In those instances, we will collect the information needed to fulfill your registration
or acknowledge your contribution, just as though it had been made on paper. That information
will be maintained and protected in accordance with the Privacy Act, 5 U.S.C. 552a,
which means that it will be secured in transit to us and once received. Your contributions
are processed through secure PayPal ecommerce solution.
Disclosure of Information Collected Through This Web site
The collection of information through pasadena.edu and the disclosure of that information
are subject to the provisions of the Internet Security and Privacy Act. PCC will only
collect personal information through pasadena.edu or disclose personal information
collected through pasadena.edu if the user has consented to the collection or disclosure
of such personal information. The voluntary disclosure of personal information to
PCC by the user, constitutes consent to the collection and disclosure of the information
by PCC for the purposes for which the user disclosed the information to PCC.
However, PCC may collect or disclose personal information without consent if the collection
or disclosure is:
necessary to perform the statutory duties of PCC, or necessary for PCC to operate
a program authorized by law, or authorized by state or federal statute or regulation
made pursuant to a court order or by law
for the purpose of validating the identity of the user
of information to be used solely for statistical purposes that is in a form that cannot
be used to identify any particular person.
Further, the disclosure of information, including personal information, collected
through pasadena.edu is subject to the provisions of the Freedom of Information Law,
the Personal Privacy Protection Law and Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act
(FERPA).
PCC may disclose personal information to federal or state law enforcement authorities
to enforce its rights against unauthorized access or attempted unauthorized access
to PCC's information technology assets.
Use of Your Personal Information
Pasadena City College may use your personally identifiable information to inform you
of services provided and processes requiring your attention. PCC may also contact
you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential
new services.
Access to and Correction of Personal Information Collected through pasadena.edu
Users have online access to some of their Internet collected personal information
and are provided Internet access to update and correct information. Additionally any
user may submit a request to PCC's Web Administrator to determine whether personal
information pertaining to that user has been collected through pasadena.edu. Any such
request shall be made in writing and must be accompanied by reasonable proof of identity
of the user. Reasonable proof of identity may include verification of a signature,
inclusion of an identifier generally known only to the user, or similar appropriate
identification.
The address of the Web Administrator is:
Pasadena City CollegeAttn: Web Administrator, Building C, Room 1451570 E. Colorado Blvd.Pasadena, CA 91106
The Web Administrator shall, within five (5) business days of the receipt of a proper
request, provide access to the personal information; deny access in writing, explaining
the reasons therefore; or acknowledge the receipt of the request in writing, stating
the approximate date when the request will be granted or denied, which date shall
not be more than thirty (30) days from the date of the acknowledgment.
In the event that PCC has collected personal information pertaining to a user through
pasadena.edu and that information is to be provided to the user pursuant to the userâ€™s
request, the Web Administrator shall inform the user of his or her right to request
that the personal information be amended or corrected under the procedures set forth
in section 95 of the Public Officers Law.
Additional information regarding the college's policies relating the Family Educational
Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) can be found here: /admissions/records/ferpa.cfm
Confidentiality and Integrity of Personal Information Collected Through pasadena.edu
PCC is strongly committed to protecting personal information collected through pasadena.edu
against unauthorized access, use or disclosure. PCC has implemented procedures to
safeguard the integrity of its information technology assets, including, but not limited
to, authentication, authorization, monitoring, auditing, and encryption. These security
procedures have been integrated into the design, implementation, and day-to-day operations
of pasadena.edu, as well as limited employee access to personal information collected
through pasadena.edu as part of our continuing commitment to the security of electronic
content as well as the electronic transmission of information.
PCC secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure.
PCC secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers
in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure.
When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other Web
sites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer
(SSL) protocol.
For Web site security purposes and to maintain the availability of pasadena.edu for
all users, PCC employs software to monitor traffic to identify unauthorized attempts
to upload or change information or otherwise damage pasadena.edu.
Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information
or personally sensitive data through one of PCC's social network sites, such as Facebook®,
Twitter®, YouTube® or WordPress® blog, this information may be collected and used
by others.
Other Web Sites Linked from Pasadena.edu
PCC encourages you to review the privacy statements of Web sites you choose to visit
from links on pasadena.edu. PCC is not responsible for the privacy statements or other
content on Web sites outside of the Pasadena City College's family of Web sites.
Cookies
Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored by the user's browser on the
hard drive of your computer. Pasadena.edu utilizes temporary and long lasting session
cookies in certain portions of itâ€™s website to manage your interaction activities,
such as Online Orientation completion and to provide convenience or personalized features
to save you time, such as personalized Quick Links. You have the ability to accept
or decline cookies via your browser preferences and may decline if you prefer. If
you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive
features of this site.
Disclaimer
The information provided in this privacy policy should not be construed as giving
business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information
provided through pasadena.edu.
Limitation of Liability
PCC attempts to maintain the highest accuracy of content on its web site. Any errors
or omissions should be reported for investigation.
PCC makes no claims, promises, or guarantees about the absolute accuracy, completeness,
or adequacy of the contents of this web site and expressly disclaims liability for
errors and omissions in the contents of this web site. No warranty of any kind, implied,
expressed, or statutory, including but not limited to the warranties of non-infringement
of third party rights, title, merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose, and
freedom from computer virus, is given with respect to the contents of this web site
or its hyperlinks to other Internet resources. References or links in this web site
to any specific commercial products, processes, or services, or the use of any trade,
firm, or corporation name are for the information and convenience of the public, and
do not constitute endorsement, recommendation, or favoring by the State of California,
or its employees or agents.
Contact Information
For questions regarding this Internet privacy policy, please contact the Web Administrator
via e-mail at wecoord@pasadena.edu or by regular mail at:
Pasadena City CollegeAttn: Web Administrator, Building C, Room 1451570 E. Colorado Blvd.Pasadena, CA 91106
If you believe that Pasadena City College has not adhered to this Internet Privacy
Statement, please contact the above. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to
promptly determine and remedy the problem.
Changes to this Statement
This Statement of Internet Privacy Policy is subject to change without notice.
PCC will occasionally update this Statement of Internet Privacy Policy as the conditions
and website change. PCC encourages you to periodically review this Policy to be informed
of how PCC is protecting your information.
